It's finally here.
Midori's first love.
Could it be…
you have come to dislike us?
But Midori is completely
unused to romance.
I…
Mr. Nishigami…
A typhoon is coming soon.
Those five you are
so close with will all die.
Your recent actions
have been unacceptable.
You haven't forgotten
your mission, have you?
You taught us many things and helped us.
So we've had a fun and safe vacation.
Three.
Two.
One.
Thank you for always protecting the villa.
Typhoon No.13 is expected
to maintain its extreme intensity,
and make landfall
in the Kanto region late tonight.
The typhoon scares me!
This typhoon is quite strong, huh.
It will probably miss us.
It's always like that.
The news is just trying to scare us.
That's true.
You think work might be canceled tomorrow,
but then you wake up, and it's sunny.
Looks like it will rain
quite a bit this time.
I don't think I can fish in this weather.
Then, what can we do indoors?
Okay!
Tonight, let's hold one of these!
-Huh?
-What?
-What is "these"?
-Here goes.
What is it?
Shut up!
-We will hold a card tournament!
-Huh?
In this day and age?
Why not? I found these cards here.
-I wonder if Grandma used them?
-They're big.
-They are, right?
-What game should we play?
-They're huge!
-Old Maid!
-Old Maid using Grandma's cards!
-So big!
-The heck is that?
-Stop it!
This is the Old Maid card.
I drew an old maid!
Grandma, I'm sorry!
Here.
-You don't have it?
-Pick whichever.
-You don't have it, right? Okay.
-Nope, I don't.
Okay! Huh, what is this? Can I pick?
-Will Mr. Nishigami come?
-Oh, sorry!
He may be busy preparing for the typhoon.
Right.
Looks like a fun time, huh?
A barbecue?
JAPAN DIVISION HEAD
LADY YOMI
Nice to be young.
Sorry for calling you here so suddenly.
Now…
This is your final warning.
Tonight is the night.
Let me tell you what will happen
if you break the code.
Every human involved with you
will have all Grim Reaper
related memories erased.
In other words,
they will forget your very existence.
Every memory you shared this summer.
The feelings that girl has for you
will also disappear.
And of course,
you yourself will be punished
by the laws of the underworld.
Calm down.
It's just a difference of a few decades.
Those humans will just meet
their demise a bit earlier.
Do your job, as you have always done.
Don't forget.
You're a Grim Reaper.
Time flows differently
for us and for humans.
I understand.
No lying!
It's a real weak one!
A weak one.
How about mine?
I wonder what it's supposed to be?
Did you copy it from a manga
you liked back in grade school?
Hmm…
Doesn't this look like Mr. Nishigami?
Oh, really?
Yeah.
So he's been your dream guy
ever since you were a kid?
-Right?
-I wonder.
Is Mr. Nishigami not coming?
Yeah…
On a day like this,
shouldn't he come to check on us?
I guess he's busy with the typhoon,
since he's the caretaker here.
Oh, it's him!
What? Mr. Nishigami?
Mr. Nishigami.
Mr. Nishigami, please sit in the middle.
-Six cans!
-Okay!
Konta, another round of Old Maid?
I'm tired of Old Maid already!
It's fine.
-Isn't there anything else?
-What?
I bet you haven't played cards
in a while either.
How long since your last game?
Still, I wonder if we'll be okay.
Is it always like this around here?
No, this typhoon
is an especially large one.
I'm sure it will be fine.
It's not raining that much yet.
Will you have dinner with us today too?
But, Midori, do we still have food?
I don't think we can buy anything now.
True, feels like it will start raining
the moment we step outside.
Yeah. So today, with leftovers,
I'll make Napolitan pasta.
Oh, Napolitan!
We can't do a barbecue,
but I'll make a yummy napolitan.
Sure.
Mr. Nishigami,
you should just call it a day.
Yeah, that's right.
Let's drink.
-Here you go.
-Yeah!
Thank you.
What are we playing?
-Daifugo!
What?
Mr. Nishigami?
Such a thing is impossible!
I mean,
the typhoon passes through multiple areas,
so I can't just divert it by myself.
It's beyond me.
Besides, such an urgent request?
A god on my level can't do it.
Don't look so scary! I can't do it!
You know if we try anything,
we will be punished, right?
Besides, what you want to stop
is the landslide, right?
So, why not ask the Mountain God?
The Mountain God. Go ask them, yeah.
No one can stop that typhoon,
but the Mountain God…
The ground is within her control.
If you ask them,
they can do something. Okay?
Oh, he's gone.
Where did he go? Huh?
At this rate,
he will be punished, for sure.
What are you saying?
You're a Grim Reaper, aren't you?
Please stop the landslide
that is about to happen.
What are you saying?
Lady Yomi already warned you many times.
Don't interfere
with the destiny of humans.
-Yes.
-Listen up, Reaper.
Even if you violate
the laws of the underworld
and give up your existence to save them,
they'll die in a few decades anyway.
A few decades.
No.
Some of them might only have a few years.
For this past month,
I've been watching those humans
spending time at that villa.
They don't work, they don't study.
They just idle away every day
playing around.
Even if you save them tonight,
their self-indulgent and meaningless life
will only be extended by a little bit.
I believe
that the time they spent at this villa
will pave the way for their future.
Besides, to them, it's a long time.
A few decades to them should be equivalent
to hundreds…
No.
Thousands of years for us.
You talk just like a human now!
You…
You'll be erased like sand
by Lady Yomi, you know.
Like sand…
A Reaper like me will die…
It's strange.
Right now, for the first time,
I truly feel
like I'm alive.
Seriously!
A Grim Reaper, taken in by humans…
That's a first for me.
I, too,
have been watching the humans
living in Tatsumi Town for a long time.
And while there are humans who fulfill
their lifespan, less than 100 years,
and meet death peacefully,
there are also those
who die young due to illness or accidents.
You…
want to extend the time
of those young people, don't you?
Even if you must offer
your own existence in exchange.
A Grim Reaper, breaking the code.
How interesting.
Up on that mountain,
there is an old shrine nobody visits.
Try going there.
All natural disasters around here
are governed by that shrine.
If you go there, you may be able…
to change something.
Not that I care.
Over here, the rain and wind from earlier
have temporarily stopped.
Could this be the calm before the storm?
However, the intensity of the typhoon
has not dropped.
Please do not let your guard down.
Where did he go?
A Grim Reaper in human form?
A Grim Reaper…
Are you here to collect me?
I'm sorry.
I can't die. Yeah.
Because I'm a god.
Japan is home to myriad gods.
I control all weather!
The venerable Dragon God!
Today, without a doubt,
a landslide will occur.
You cannot change that absolute fact.
Goodbye.
They're being blown away!
It's dangerous to stay here.
Mr. Nishigami?
I have met you before.
Who are you?
It was the best vacation.
Thank you.
Subtitle translation by: Nix S.